Guide to the Lavoisier Manuscripts and Graphics Collection, circa 1750-1834 (bulk)
Lavoisier Manuscripts and Graphics Collection, circa 1750-1834 (bulk)
- Series IX. Plates made by Marie Anne Lavoisier for the Traité élémentaire de chimie, 1789
  - Planche XIII
    - Planche XIII: preliminary print (Box 21, Folder 8)
      Abstract: Heavily annotated in ink, including letters and numbers (fig. 3 still labeled P instead of N). "Planche XIII" on top left corner. Other annotations as follows: Fig. 2 V "l'ouverture plus grand"; Fig. 2 A redrawn to larger sizes twice with "la cornue plus grande" (change does not appear in final edition); Fig. 3. X "l'ouverture plus grande"; Fig. 8 near A box drawn in by hand "porte latérale"; Fig. 4 "le trou plus grand"; Fig. 7 "diminuer le tour"; Fig. 10 H "les traits trop fins" "effacer la ligne verticale" crossed out (change does not appear in final edition).
    - Planche XIII: preliminary print (Box 21, Folder 9)
      Abstract: Ink annotations of numbers and letters of figures. "PLANCHE VIII" in capital letters top right. On Fig.3, "P" crossed out and replaced with "N" (evidenced in final copy).
    - Planche XIII: proof (Box 21, Folder 10)
      Abstract: Adjustments made (trou plus grand etc) brown stain on bottom left corner.
    - Planche XIII: proof (Box 21, Folder 11)
      Abstract: Same print as 21.10
  - Plates engraved by J. Pass, after Marie Anne Lavoisier's work and Henry Lascelles' drawings, describing the modern chemical apparatus, London, 1800-1801.
    - CHEMISTRY: Plate I., November 15, 1800 (Box 22, Folder 1)
      Abstract: Includes apparatus similar to elements from Lavoisier's drawings. Bottom inscription "The Modern Chemical Apparatus. No. 1" "London. Published as the Act directs. Nov.r 15. 1800 by J. Wilkes." "J. Pass sculp.t"
      Physical Description: Colored print
    - CHEMISTRY: Plate II., November 20, 1800 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      Abstract: Includes chemical apparatus. Bottom inscription "The Modern Chemical Apparatus. No. 2" "London. Published as the Act directs. Nov.r 20. 1800 by J. Wilkes." "J. Pass sculp.t"
    - CHEMISTRY: Plate III., December 1, 1800 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      Abstract: Includes seven chemical apparatus setups similar to elements from Lavoisier's drawings. Bottom inscription "The Modern Chemical Apparatus. No. 3" "London. Published as the Act directs. Dec.r 1. 1800 by J. Wilkes." "J. Pass sculp.t"
    - CHEMISTRY: Plate V., December 22, 1800 (Box 22, Folder 4)
      Abstract: Includes three setups of chemical apparatus similar to Planche IV Fig.1. Bottom inscription "The Modern Chemical Apparatus. No. 5" "London. Published as the Act directs. Dec.r 22. 1800 by J. Wilkes." "J. Pass sculp.t"
    - CHEMISTRY: Plate VII., February 21, 1801 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      Abstract: Includes chemical apparatus. Bottom inscription: "Van Marum's Gazometer" "London. Published as the Act directs. Feb.y 21. 1801 by J. Wilkes." "J. Pass sculp.t" and "Hen.y. Larcelles del.t"
    - CHEMISTRY: Plate IX., March 9, 1801 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      Abstract: Includes chemical apparatus. Bottom inscription: "1. New Gazometer of the Philosophical Society of London. - 2 to 4. DeVigne's Apparatus for saturating Water with Gas. - 5 and 6. Apparatus for freezing Mercury." "London. Published as the Act directs. March 9. 1801 by J. Wilkes." "J.Pass sculp.t" and "H. Lascelles del.t"
    - CHEMISTRY: Plate X., March 2, 1801 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      Abstract: Includes chemical apparatus. Bottom inscription: "1. Nen Steelyards for weighing Gasses. 2. Apparatus for the Combustion of the Diamond." "London. Published as the Act directs. March 2. 1801 by J. Wilkes." "J. Pass sculp.t" and "H. Lascelles del.t"
    - CHEMISTRY: Plate XI., March 10, 1801 (Box 22, Folder 8)
      Abstract: Clearly copied from Planche VI of the Traité élémentaire de chimie. Includes chemical apparatus. Bottom inscription "The Calorimeter of Lavoisier and La Place" "London. Published as the Act directs. March 10. 1801 by J. Wilkes." "J. Pass sculp.t" and "H. Lascelles del.t"
- Series X. Other Drawings
  - Plans of Buildings
    - Plan General du Jardin…Madame de Pumfort" (Box 24, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: Pen and ink and watercolor drawing with pencil underdrawing
      Size and Notes on Paper: 24" x 38"
      Restriction: Possible mold contamination
    - House and garden in ink and colored liquid medium (Box 24, Folder 2)
      Physical Description: Pen and ink with watercolor washes and black ink inscriptions
      Size and Notes on Paper: 24.25" x 18.25"
    - Building plan in brown ink on coated paper (Box 25b, Folder 3)
      Physical Description: Watercolor or dyes wash, pen & ink
      Size and Notes on Paper: 24.75" x 36". Four attached sheets.
      Restriction: Should not be handled by patrons
    - Plan of building in color- liquid mediums (Box 25c, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: Multicolor liquid medium with pen & ink, pencil underdrawing
      Size and Notes on Paper: 20.5" x 13.25". Two designs on two sheets of paper.
    - Plan in dark brown to black ink (Box 25c, Folder 2)
      Physical Description: pen & ink with pencil underdrawing
      Size and Notes on Paper: 9.75" x 12.5". Two attached sheets of paper.
    - Colored architectural drawings (Box 25c, Folder 3)
      Physical Description: Multicolor watercolor with pen & ink, pencil underdrawing
      Size and Notes on Paper: 19.75" x 13.5". Two designs on two sheets of paper.
    - Architectural plan in black pencil on paper (Box 25c, Folder 4)
      Physical Description: Graphite pencil architectural plan with pencil inscription
      Size and Notes on Paper: 9.75" x 15.25". Has watermark in center.
    - Elevation plan (Box 25d, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: Multicolor wash and pen & ink
      Size and Notes on Paper: 18.25" x 12.75"
    - Architectural plan (Box 25d, Folder 2)
      Physical Description: Multicolor wash with pen & ink with pencil underdrawing
      Size and Notes on Paper: 17.5" x 23.25"
    - Building plan in brown ink (Box 25e, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: pen & ink with some multicolor washes
      Size and Notes on Paper: 18 3/8" x 42". Watermarked.
    - Plan in pen & ink with gray, black and dark pink washes (Box 25e, Folder 2)
      Physical Description: pen & ink and pencil drawing with color washes
      Size and Notes on Paper: 18.25" x 20"
    - Ferme de Taille (Box 25e, Folder 3)
      Size and Notes on Paper: 19.25" x 13.5"
  - Plans of Madame Lavoisier's Residence in Paris
    - Sketch with grey wash and iron gall ink embellishment (Box 25b, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: Grey wash drawing with iron-gall embellishment
      Size and Notes on Paper: 10.5" x 7 5/8". Laid with countermark in the center.
    - Plans of rooms in pen and ink (Box 25b, Folder 2)
      Physical Description: Architectural plan in pen & ink with some pencil
      Size and Notes on Paper: 8.5" x 10.5"
    - "Plan d'un terrain…" (pen and ink?) (Box 25b, Folder 4)
      Physical Description: Lithograph with some additions in pencil
      Size and Notes on Paper: 17.5" x 23.5". Countermark on the right half and watermark on left.
    - Map with text, hand drawn in brown, red ink and pencil (Box 25b, Folder 5)
      Physical Description: Pen and ink and pencil map with iron-gall text below
      Size and Notes on Paper: 20.25" x 27". Laid with watermark at the right side.
    - Boulevard plan, exterior Paris (Box 27a, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: Planographic print with hand multicolored washes
      Size and Notes on Paper: 24" x 51". Two sheets attached along edges
    - Black pencil sketch of house plan (Box 27b, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: Architectural sketch in pencil
      Size and Notes on Paper: 11" x 9". Laid with countermark along left edge.
    - Sketch in green (Box 27b, Folder 2)
      Physical Description: pen & ink with green watercolor and pencil underdrawing
      Size and Notes on Paper: 9" x 12"
    - Unfinished black pencil sketch (Box 27b, Folder 3)
      Physical Description: Pencil sketch on both sides
      Size and Notes on Paper: 11.25" x 8.75". Laid with countermark at the left.
    - Small pen and ink drawing of gazebo (Box 27c, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: pen & ink architectural drawing with pencil underdrawing
      Size and Notes on Paper: 5.5" x 9"
    - Sketch in ink and graphite pencil on blue paper (Box 27c, Folder 2)
      Size and Notes on Paper: 11.75" x 10". Laid with grape watermark in the center.
    - House/garden plan in black ink and red liquid medium (Box 27c, Folder 3)
      Physical Description: Plan of house and garden in pen & ink with color washes
      Size and Notes on Paper: 6.25" x 10.75". Laid with countermark at the lower left.
    - Plan in black and brown ink and pink liquid medium (Box 27c, Folder 4)
      Physical Description: pen & ink sketch with liquid washes and iron gall inscriptions
      Size and Notes on Paper: 3" x 8"
    - Plan in black and brown ink and pink liquid medium (Box 27d, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: Plan in pen & ink with washes and iron gall inscriptions
      Size and Notes on Paper: 5.25" x 8"
    - Plan in black, red and grey liquid medium (Box 27d, Folder 2)
      Physical Description: pen & ink architectural plan with red and black washes and pencil inscriptions
      Size and Notes on Paper: 5.75" x 9.75"
    - Unfinished pencil sketch (Box 27d, Folder 3)
      Physical Description: Graphite pencil plan
      Size and Notes on Paper: 5.25" x 6.75"
    - Unfinished in black ink and red color (Box 27d, Folder 4)
      Physical Description: Unfinished architectural plan in pen & ink with color washes and pencil underdrawing
      Size and Notes on Paper: 9.5" x 11.75". Part of a countermark at the lower right.
    - Sketch of building façade in green (Box 27e, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: pen & ink architectural drawing with multicolor washes and pencil underdrawing
      Size and Notes on Paper: 11" x 14". Two pieces of paper, countermark in the center of the larger piece.
    - Plan in grey and pink (Box 27e, Folder 2)
      Physical Description: Architectural plan in pen & ink with coloring and iron gall inscriptions
      Size and Notes on Paper: 15.25" x 20". Laid with watermark (left side) and countermark (right side) of the sheet
    - Façade of building in pen, black ink, and pink (Box 27e, Folder 3)
      Physical Description: pen & ink drawing with pink wash and pencil underdrawing
      Size and Notes on Paper: 11" x 15". Laid with watermark in the center of the larger dimensions paper and countermark in the center of the paper attached.
    - Overhead plan in ink, pink and grey liquid medium (Box 27e, Folder 4)
      Physical Description: pen & ink architectural plan with grey and pink washes and pencil underdrawing with pencil inscriptions
      Size and Notes on Paper: 9.75" x 15.25". Laid with countermarks in the center.
    - Plan in black and brown ink and pink liquid medium (Box 27e, Folder 5)
      Physical Description: pen & ink architectural plan with pink and black washes, pencil underdrawing and iron-gall inscriptions
      Size and Notes on Paper: 9" x 13.5"
    - Sketch of interior with canopy bed (Box 27g, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: pen & ink with watercolor and pencil underdrawing
      Size and Notes on Paper: 8.5" x 17.25"
    - Architectural sketch in black pencil on blue paper (Box 27g, Folder 2)
      Physical Description: Architectural sketch in pencil (on both sides)
      Size and Notes on Paper: 18.25" x 11.5". Laid with countermark.
    - Architectural sketch in pink (Box 27g, Folder 3)
      Physical Description: Architectural sketch in pen & ink, pencil and pink coloring with red & black ink inscriptions
      Size and Notes on Paper: 18.5" x 24.5"
    - Sketch in graphite pencil (Box 27g, Folder 4)
      Physical Description: Architectural pencil sketch
      Size and Notes on Paper: 11" x 17". Laid with watermark in the center.
    - Plan in grey, pink, green liquid medium (Box 27h, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: Architectural plan in pen & ink with color washes and iron gall ink inscriptions
      Size and Notes on Paper: 12.75" x 18". Laid with "Vander Ley" countermark in the center
    - Pencil and ink sketch of house (with red ink) (Box 27h, Folder 2)
      Physical Description: Architectural pen & ink sketch with red ink subscriptions
      Size and Notes on Paper: 15.75" x 17.75"
    - Unfinished black pencil sketch (Box 27h, Folder 3)
      Size and Notes on Paper: 11.25" x 17.5". Laid with grape watermark in the center.
    - Architectural sketch in black pencil (Box 27i, Folder 1)
      Size and Notes on Paper: 20.5" x 26.5". Laid with large watermark in the center.
    - Sketch on paper in pencil and black ink (Box 27i, Folder 2)
      Physical Description: pen & ink and pencil sketch with black ink inscriptions
      Size and Notes on Paper: 17" x 22.25"
    - City plan, near Paris (Box 27i, Folder 3)
      Physical Description: Planographic print with hand multicolor washes
      Size and Notes on Paper: 21.25" x 22.25". Four sheets of paper attached along the edges
    - Black pencil sketch with yellow and blue (Box 27i, Folder 4)
      Physical Description: Architectural drawing in pen & ink, and pencil hand-colored with watercolor
      Size and Notes on Paper: 17" x 18"
    - "Plan d'un terrain…" (pen and ink?) (Box 27j, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: Lithograph of architectural plan
      Size and Notes on Paper: 17.5" x 23.5". Laid with Fleur-De-Lis watermark at the right half and countermark on the left
    - "Plan d'un terrain…" (pen and ink?) (Box 27j, Folder 2)
      Size and Notes on Paper: 17.5" x 23.5"
    - "Plan d'un terrain…" (pen and ink?) (Box 27j, Folder 3)
      Physical Description: Architectural hand colored (multicolor) lithograph with pencil additions
    - Unfinished plan in black pencil, ink, and pink medium (Box 27k, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: Architectural sketch in pencil, ink, and pink medium
      Size and Notes on Paper: 20" x 23"
    - Unfinished architectural sketch in black pencil and ink (Box 27k, Folder 2)
      Physical Description: Architectural sketch in black pencil and ink
      Size and Notes on Paper: 18" x 26.75"
    - Sketch in pencil and brown ink (Box 27k, Folder 3)
      Physical Description: Pen & brown ink and pencil with dimensions (architectural details) in brown ink
      Size and Notes on Paper: 19.25" x 17"
    - Pen and ink sketch with red liquid medium (Box 28b, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: pen & ink with pencil and burgundy wash
      Size and Notes on Paper: 11" x 18". Laid with countermark in the center.
  - Maps Used by Lavoisier as Fermier General
    - Hand drawn map in several inks and liquid green colorant (Box 24, Folder 3)
      Physical Description: Pen and ink (red, black, green) drawing with green and green-grey washes and red pencil preparatory grids
      Size and Notes on Paper: 21.5" x 20"
    - "Map of Loire-Saane Canal" (Box 27f, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: Hand-colored Intaglio print with pencil lines, note in iron-gall ink is attacted to verso of right side of map
      Size and Notes on Paper: 9.25" x 25.5"
    - "Projection Geo-Spherique" map (Box 27f, Folder 2)
      Physical Description: Intaglio with hand colored black ink
      Size and Notes on Paper: 18" x 23.5". Laid paper with watermark on the right and countermark on the left
    - "Plan de partie de lazcenal de Marseille", in ink and washes (Box 27f, Folder 3)
      Physical Description: Pen and ink with color washes with pencil underdrawing
      Size and Notes on Paper: 17.5" x 8"
    - "Plan du Fort de Gviol" drawn in ink, pencil, and colorants (Box 27f, Folder 4)
      Physical Description: Pen and ink plan with washes with iron-gall inscriptions
      Size and Notes on Paper: 17.5" x 13.75". Lower sheet has a watermark below the center.
    - "La France" (Box 28a, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: Intaglio print
      Size and Notes on Paper: 9" x 12". Laid with countermark at the upper margin.
    - "La France" (Box 28a, Folder 2)
      Size and Notes on Paper: 9" x 12". Laid with a part of the watermark at the upper margin.
    - Map of France in dark brown/black ink (Box 28b, Folder 2)
      Physical Description: Preliminary of map in pen & ink
      Size and Notes on Paper: 14.5" x 9.5". Laid with countermarks in the center.
    - Preliminary map in black ink with pencil grids (Box 28b, Folder 3)
      Physical Description: Map preliminary in black ink and pencil grids
      Size and Notes on Paper: 14.25" x 9.5". Laid with Fleur-de-Lis watermark in the center.
    - "France" (Box 28b, Folder 4)
      Physical Description: Printed in intaglio from incomplete plate
      Size and Notes on Paper: 11.5" x 15.25". Laid with part of watermark at the upper part.
    - "France" (Box 28b, Folder 5)
      Size and Notes on Paper: 11.5" x 15.25". Laid with watermark in upper central part.
    - "Carte de France" map (Box 28c, Folder 1)
      Size and Notes on Paper: 17" x 23". Laid with watermark in the center.
    - "Carte du Compte-Venaissin" map (Box 28c, Folder 2)
      Size and Notes on Paper: 20" x 15". Laid paper with watermark (approximately center)
    - "Direction D'Angers" map (Box 28c, Folder 3)
      Physical Description: Hand-colored intaglio print with iron-gall ink inscriptions
      Size and Notes on Paper: 23" x 32"
    - "Direction D'Angers" map (Box 28c, Folder 4)
      Physical Description: Hand-colored Intaglio print with iron-gall ink inscriptions
      Size and Notes on Paper: 22.5" x 31.5"
    - Map in brown ink with colorants, washes (Box 28c, Folder 5)
      Physical Description: Pen and ink drawing with washes and iron-gall inscriptions; pencil underdrawing
      Size and Notes on Paper: 19" x 27.5"
  - Mineralogical Studies
    - Intaglio mineralogical map of Paris with red ink (Box 26a, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: Map in ink and graphite pencil
      Size and Notes on Paper: 14.25" x 12". Watermarked and countermarked
    - Map, near Lazio, in brown ink (iron gall?) (Box 26a, Folder 2)
      Physical Description: Map in iron-gall ink and pencil
      Size and Notes on Paper: 10.125" x 13.5". Laid with watermark.
    - Untitled map (Box 26a, Folder 3)
      Physical Description: Map in iron-gall ink
      Size and Notes on Paper: 13.5" x 8.75". Laid with countermarks.
    - Map, near Bergosam (Box 26a, Folder 4)
      Size and Notes on Paper: 9" x 13.5". Laid with watermark in the center.
    - Untitled map (Box 26a, Folder 5)
      Physical Description: Unfinished map in iron-gall ink and pencil
      Size and Notes on Paper: 10.75" x 15.25". Laid with watermark at the left part.
    - Drawing in pen and ink (Box 26b, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: Map in black ink with pencil underdrawing
      Size and Notes on Paper: 9.25" x 11.75"
    - "Carte Mineralogique de la Champagne" intaglio print (Box 26b, Folder 2)
      Physical Description: Intaglio (etching) print
      Size and Notes on Paper: 13.75" x 20.75". Laid with watermark in the center.
    - "Franche Compte" in black and brown ink and pencil (Box 26b, Folder 3)
      Physical Description: Brown ink and pencil
      Size and Notes on Paper: 19.5" x 14.5". Laid with watermark and countermark.
    - Mineralogical map in black, brown, and red ink (Box 26c, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: Intaglio print (map) with red ink & pencil corrections
      Size and Notes on Paper: 14" x 14.5". Laid with countermarks.
    - "Plan et Profil" (Box 26c, Folder 2)
      Physical Description: Plan printed in black
      Size and Notes on Paper: 21" x 16.75". Laid paper with countermark.
    - "Carte Mineralogique de L'Italie" (Box 26c, Folder 3)
      Physical Description: Map in pencil, ink and green washes
      Size and Notes on Paper: 17.75" x 13.5". Laid with watermark.
    - "Nouveau Plan D'Orleans" intaglio print (Box 26c, Folder 4)
      Size and Notes on Paper: 11.75" x 17.25"
    - "Carte Mineralogique," near Vexin. Intaglio print (Box 26d, Folder 1)
      Size and Notes on Paper: 13.5" x 20.5". Laid with countermarks in the center.
    - "Carte Mineralogique," near Valois. Intaglio print (Box 26d, Folder 2)
      Size and Notes on Paper: 13 7/8" x 21". Laid with watermark in the center.
    - "Carte Mineralogique," near Lorraine. Intaglio print (Box 26d, Folder 3)
      Size and Notes on Paper: 15" x 19.5". Laid with watermark on the left part.
    - "Carte Mineralogique," near L'Alsace (Box 26d, Folder 4)
      Size and Notes on Paper: 16.25" x 21". Laid with countermarks on the right part.
    - Map of area near Aix La Chapelle. Intaglio print (Box 26e, Folder 1)
      Size and Notes on Paper: 13.5" x 20.75"
    - Map drawn in red and black ink (partial) (Box 26e, Folder 2)
      Physical Description: Red & black ink with pencil underdrawing
      Size and Notes on Paper: 9" x 20.5". Laid with watermark.
    - "Plan de Soissons" intaglio, hand colored (Box 26e, Folder 3)
      Physical Description: Intaglio print with handcoloring (washes)
      Size and Notes on Paper: 19.75" x 26.5". Laid with watermark in center.
    - Preliminary map in brown ink (Box 26e, Folder 4)
      Physical Description: Map in brown ink with pencil underwriting
      Size and Notes on Paper: 19" x 24". Laid with watermark and countermark.
    - "Carte Topographica" of ancient Rome. Intaglio print and brown ink (Box 26f, Folder 1)
      Physical Description: Intaglio print with iron-gall marking
      Size and Notes on Paper: 17.75" x 25.75"
      Restriction: Mold contamination
    - "Nouveau Plan de Lisle de Corse" Intaglio print (Box 26f, Folder 2)
      Physical Description: Intaglio print with iron-gall notations and marking
      Size and Notes on Paper: 23.75" x 33.75". Laid with grapes countermark.
    - Intaglio mineralogical map with hand coloring (Box 26f, Folder 3)
      Physical Description: Intaglio print with multicolor line with pencil notes and sketches (verso)
      Size and Notes on Paper: 22.5" x 31.5". Laid paper with watermark.
    - "Carte de Chartreuse" Intaglio print (Box 26f, Folder 4)
      Physical Description: Intaglio print with pencil and brown ink marking
      Size and Notes on Paper: 16.75" x 32.75"
    - "Direction De Laval", drawing in pencil, black and colored ink (Box 26f, Folder 5)
      Physical Description: Map in iron-gall ink with multicolor
      Size and Notes on Paper: 19" x 24 7/8". Laid with countermark at the upper central park
- Series XI. Lavoisier Artifacts and Memorabilia
  - Madame Lavoisier's Travel Case (Box 29)
  - Shoe Buckles, Undated (Box 29)
  - Travel Knife/Fork, Undated (Box 29)
  - Madame Lavoisier's Notebook, Undated (Box 29)
  - Crucible with Spoon, Undated (Box 29)
  - 6 Jetons and a Coin Purse (Box 29a)
    Four of the Jetons read: "Surete Dans La Confiance" Two jetons from the period of Lavoisier's membership in the Acadamie des Sciences.
  - 9 Jetons and a coin purse (Box 29b)
    Jetons read: "Agriculture and Comerce"
  - 8 Jetons and a Knitted Coin Purse, c. 1785 (Box 29c)
    Jetons read" "Munificence Royale" - "Ex Utilitate Decus" From the Royal Scociety of Agriculture in Paris
  - 2 Medals, Unknown, 1952 (Box 29d)
    Caisse d'Escompte - Motto "Surete Dans La Confiance".
    Commemorative Bronze Medal of Lavoisier made in 1952
  - Two Fortune Telling Games in Wooden Boxes, Undated (Box 29e)
  - Four Science and Medicine Medals, 1919, 1958, 1963 (Box 29f)
  - 2 Briefcases owned by Lavoisier (one when he was a child) (Box 30-31)
  - Seven Plates from the Title Page of Traite Elementaire, Undated (Box 41)
  - Mason's Apronin frame, Undated (Box 47)
  - Blue Silk Collar in frame, Undated (Box 48)
  - Lavoisier's Wooden Ladder